Register of the Paul Robert Hanna Papers, 1920-1997
Hoover Institution Archives
Paul Robert Hanna papers,
1920-1997
77098
Hanna, Paul Robert, 1902-
236 manuscript boxes, 4 cubic foot boxes, 8 oversize boxes, 1 oversize packet, 21 envelopes, 1 oversize folder, 1 motion picture film reel, 1 video cassette (104 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, printed matter, and photographs, of the American educator and director of the Stanford International Development Education Center from 1963-1968. Materials relate to education in the United States, the Philippines, and developing countries in general.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Indexing Terms
Stanford International Development Education Center.; Education--United States.; International education.; United States--Foreign relations.; Education--Philippines.; Education--Developing countries.; Moving pictures; Video tapes.
Biographical Note
1902, June 21 born, Sioux City, Iowa
1924 A.B., Philosophy magna cum laude, Hamline University
1925 A.M., Columbia University
1925-1927 Superintendent of Schools, West Winfield, New York
1928-1935 Research associate, Lincoln School, Columbia University
1929 Ph.D., Columbia University
1930-1935 Assistant Professor, Teachers College, Columbia University
1930-1975 Designer and senior author, Investigating Man's World, a series of social science texbooks, Scott, Foresman and Co.
1930-1944 Founder and Member, editorial board, Building America
1933-1940 Consultant to Tennessee Valley Authority
1935-1937 Associate professor of Education, Stanford University
1936-1939 National Director, U.S. Council for Conservation Education
1936-1966 Member, editorial board, World Book Encyclopedia
1937 Doctor of Pedagogy (honorary), Hamline University
1937-1954 Professor of Education, Stanford University
1939-1942 Consultant to National Resources Planning Board
1940-1942 Consultant to Coordinator of Intern-American Affairs, with assignments to South America and Central America
1941-1945 Member, Curriculum Committee, National Council for Social Studies
1942-1944 Director, Stanford University Services (war contracts for research and training)
Consultant to U.S. Secretary of War on Army Specialized Training Program
1942-1945 Consultant to War Relocation Authority
1944-1958 Staff and Advisory Committee, W.K. Kellogg Foundation
1947 Consultant to U.S. Secretary of War on re-education of Germany
1948-1960 Member, editorial board, Encyclopedia Britannica Films
1949 Member, UNESCO consultative educational mission to the Philippines
1952-1953 Director, Educational Division, U.S. Mutual Security Agency, Philippines
1953-56 Coordinator, University of the Philippines-Stanford University Contract, U.S. Agency for International Development
1954-1967 Lee L. Jacks Professor of Education, Stanford University
1954-1968 Founding Director, Stanford International Development Education Center (SIDEC)
1955-1958 Member, U.S. National Commission for UNESCO Committee on Fundemental Society
1955-1960 Member, Committee on Institutional Projects Abroad, American Council of Education
1956-1960 Coordinator, Philippines Department of Education-Stanford University Contract, U.S. Agency for International Development
1958 Visiting professor, Harvard University
1962-1967 Member, Committee on International Education Policy of the Commission on Education and International Affairs of the American Council on Education
1963 Acting Dean, School of Education, Stanford University Editor, Education: An Instrument of National Goals, McGraw-Hill
1963-1969 Consultant, Cooperative Research Branch, U.S. Office of Education
1964-1968 Member, Commission on International Education of the American Council of Education
Chairman, Committee on International Relations, American Educational Research Association
Member, Committee on Education and Human Development of Education and World Affairs
1964-1972 Member, Committee on Atlantic Studies of the Atlantic Council and Atlantic Institute
1964-1969 Educational advisor, Elementary School Professional Education Book Series, Houghton Mifflin Co.
1964-1970 Member, Editorial Board, American Educational Press
1965 Senior Fellow, East-West Center, Honolulu
1966 Co-author, Geography in the Teaching of Social Studies -Concepts and Skills, Houghton Mifflin Co.
Chairman, U.S. Department of State Team to Yugoslavia on Educational and Cultural Exchanges
Principal researcher, Phoneme -Grapheme Correspondences as Cues to Spelling Improvement, U.S. Government Printing Office
1967 American specialist, U.S. Department of State, assigned to four African national governments on educational reforms
1968 Director, Stanford Asia Foundation Seminar, Role of Higher Education in Asian Nation Building, held in Korea
1968-69 Chairman, National Evaluation Committee for Peace Corps/University Relations
1968- Emeritus Jacks Professor and Emeritus Director of SIDEC, Stanford University
1969 Co-author, The United States and International Education, The National Society for the Study of Education
1970 Co-author, Spelling: Structure and Strategies, Houghton Mifflin Co.
1970-1975 Member, U.S. National Commission for UNESCO
1973-1976 Member, California Citizens Advisory Committee on State Parks and Recreation
1974- Senior Research Fellow, Hoover Institution, Stanford University
1975-1977 Member, Aspen Institute's National Commission on Coping with Interdependence
1981 Co-author, Frank Lloyd Wright's Hanna House: The Clients' Report, MIT Press
1981 Appointed to the Presidential Task Force on Arts and Humanities
1988, April died, Stanford, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, printed matter, and photographs, of the American educator and director of the Stanford International Development Education Center from 1963-1968. Materials relate to education in the United States, the Philippines, and developing countries in general.
Collection Contents
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1900-1978 (Box 1-12)
  Correspondence, clippings, calendars, notes, printed matter pertaining to Paul Hanna's life and career filed chronologically and by subject.
  - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arithmetic patent, 1927-28 (Folder 2)
  - Certificates
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Membership and appreciation (Folder 4)
    - Pedigree (dog) (Folder 5)
  - Chronological file
    - 1900-1933 (Folder 6)
    - 1938 (Folder 7)
    - 1947 (Folder 8)
    - 1954 (Folder 9)
    - 1957 (Folder 10)
    - 1958 (Folder 11)
    - 1960 (Folder 12)
    - 1962 (Folder 13)
    - 1963 (Folder 14)
    - 1965 (Folder 15)
    - 1966 (Folder 16)
    - 1967 (Folder 17)
    - 1968 (Folder 18)
    - 1969 (Folder 19)
    - 1970 (Folder 20)
    - 1971 (Folder 21)
    - 1973 (Folder 22)
    - 1974 (Folder 23)
    - 1975 (Folder 24)
    - 1976 (Folder 25)
    - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1978 (Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Folder 3)
  - College term papers, 1923-24 (Folder 4)
  - Columbia University, Teachers College, offer of professorship, 1938 (Folder 5)
  - Curriculum vitae (Folder 6)
  - Datebooks and calendars
    - 1950-1953 (Folder 7)
    - 1955-57 (Folder 8)
    - 1958 (Folder 9)
    - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1960-1962 (Folder 2)
    - 1963-1967 (Folder 3)
    - 1967 (Folder 4)
    - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - 1969 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1970 (Folder 5)
    - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1971 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1972 (Folder 4-5)
    - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - 1973/74 (Folder 3)
    - 1974/75 (Folder 4)
    - 1975/76 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1976/77 (Folder 2)
  - Financial records
    - 1954-1961 (Folder 3)
    - 1962-63 (Folder 4)
    - 1964-65 (Folder 5)
    - 1966-67 (Folder 6)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1970-71 (Folder 2)
    - 1972-76 (Folder 3)
    - Internal Revenue Service records
      - 1966-67 (Folder 4)
      - 1968-69 (Folder 5)
      - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - 1971 (Folder 2)
      - 1972 (Folder 3)
      - 1974 (Folder 4)
      - 1975 (Folder 5-7)
      - 1976 (Folder 8)
      - 1977 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Skyline properties (Folder 3-7)
  - Hamline University "Liner"
    - 1922 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1924 (Folder 2)
  - Report cards, grade and high school, 1910-1920 (Folder 3)
  - Retirement plan (Folder 4-5)
  - Retirement reception guestbook, 1967 (Folder 6)
  - Travel
    - General, 1958 (Folder 7)
    - Mexico, n.d. (Folder 8)
    - Hong Kong, 1953-1960 (Folder 9)
    - Taiwan, 1952-1953 (Folder 10)
    - Tokyo, 1955-1959 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - World trip, 1949 (Folder 2)
  - UNESCO, offer of directorship, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - West Winfield (New York) High School annuals, 1926-27 (Folder 4)
  - Miscellany (Folder 5)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1950-1980 (Box 12-18)
  Letters and enclosures written and received filed alphabetically by last name of correspondent or subject.
  - Adiseshiah, Malcolm S., 1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Air Affairs, 1951 (Folder 7)
  - American Association of School Administrators, 1971 (Folder 8)
  - American Educational Research Association, 1965-68 (Folder 9)
  - Anderson, C. Arnold, 1962-67 (Folder 10)
  - Andrus, J. Russell, 1966-67 (Folder 11)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1957 (Folder 12)
  - Ashby, Eric, 1963-65 (Folder 13)
  - Asia Foundation, 1964-67 (Folder 14)
  - Asia Society, 1965 (Folder 15)
  - Association of Overseas Educators, 1960-66 (Folder 16)
  - Atlantic Council, 1975-76 (Folder 17)
  - Bailey, Kenneth, 1964-1975 (Folder 18)
  - Bates, Bernarr, 1973 (Folder 19)
  - Beauchamp, George A., 1960-61 (Folder 20)
  - Bechtel, Stephen D., Sr., 1965-67 (Folder 21)
  - Beggs, Walter K., 1960 (Folder 22)
  - Benitez, Helen, 1970-71 (Folder 23)
  - Benitez, Conrado and Jose, 1969-1970 (Folder 24)
  - Benitez family, 1966-68 (Folder 25)
  - Blackerby, Philip, 1972 (Folder 26)
  - Boat trips, 1960 (Folder 27)
  - Bolibaugh, Jerry, 1970 (see also UNESCO) (Folder 28)
  - Bortz, Walter M., 1975 (Folder 29)
  - Boyce, Dudley, 1974 (Folder 30)
  - Bradley, Paul, 1971-72 (Folder 31)
  - Briggs, Reed, 1976 (Folder 32)
  - Britton, Glenn, 1969-1974 (Folder 33)
  - Brocchini, Ronald, 1974 (Folder 34)
  - Brooks, E. Howard, 1963-64 (Folder 35)
  - Bruner, Jerome S., 1960 (Folder 36)
  - Bryan, J.Y., 1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Buell, Robert R., 1967 (Folder 2)
  - Bullocks, 1972 (Folder 3)
  - Bunchana Atthakor, 1964-68 (Folder 4)
  - Burgess, Randolph, 1970 (Folder 5)
  - Buripakdi, Chalio, 1971-76 (Folder 6)
  - Butts, R. Freeman, 1964-68 (Folder 7)
  - California Conservation Council, 1975 (Folder 8)
  - California Elementary School Adminstrators' Association, 1952-1965 (Folder 9)
  - Charles, Allan E., 1975 (Folder 10)
  - Clark, Arthur, 1971 (Folder 11)
  - Commons, Dorman L., 1967 (Folder 12)
  - Commonwealth Club of California, 1968 (Folder 13)
  - Coombs, Philip H., 1963-1970 (Folder 14)
  - Cosmos Club, 1967-68 (Folder 15)
  - Corcorran, Fred M., 1977 (Folder 16)
  - Cotton, Dana M., 1957-1961 (Folder 17)
  - Cottrell, Leonard S., Jr., 1959-1967 (Folder 18)
  - Craig, Phyllis, 1974 (Folder 19)
  - Creole Foundation, 1963-69 (Folder 20)
  - Curle, Adam, 1963-67 (Folder 21)
  - Cushing, Suzanne, 1973 (Folder 22)
  - Davies, Elton M., 1975 (Folder 23)
  - Diez-Hochleitner, Ricardo, 1963-68 (Folder 24)
  - Dolby, Jim, 1974 (Folder 25)
  - Drummond, Harold D., 1976 (Folder 26)
  - Education and World Affairs, 1967-68 (Folder 27)
  - The Education Digest, 1960 (Folder 28)
  - Edwards, Paul, 196_ (Folder 29)
  - Elkus, Richard, 1975 (Folder 30)
  - Elliott, Ann, 1975 (Folder 31)
  - Emch, Arnold F., 1970 (Folder 32)
  - Ferguson, Glen W., 1969 (Folder 33)
  - Field Enterprises Educational Corporation, 1967 (Folder 34)
  - Fischer, John H., 1967 (Folder 35)
  - Fisher, Roy M., 1972-1974 (Folder 36)
  - Fordyce, Phillip R., 1968 (Folder 37)
  - Foster, Donald, 1975 (Folder 38)
  - Frankovic, Dragutin, 1967 (Folder 39)
  - Frederick, W. McD., 1972-76 (Folder 40)
  - Fritz, Emanuel, 1972 (Folder 41)
  - Frost, Joseph, 1969-1971 (Folder 42)
  - Gainey, Daniel, 1974-76 (Folder 43)
  - Gibson, Robert E., 1951-1966 (Folder 44)
  - Gibson, Weldon B., 1955-1963 (Folder 45)
  - Giddens, Paul H., 1955-1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Gill, Martin, 1974 (Folder 2)
  - Ginn, Rosemary, 1973-74 (Folder 3)
  - Glaser, Robert J., 1968 (Folder 4)
  - Gonzalez, Richard, 1974 (Folder 5)
  - Good, Loren D., 1978 (Folder 6)
  - Gordon, Lincoln, 1964-67 (Folder 7)
  - Gordon, Walton M., 1958-1962 (Folder 8)
  - Grantham, Herbert H., 1974 (Folder 9)
  - Gray, Gary M., 1972 (Folder 10)
  - Gregorio, Arlen, 1973-74 (Folder 11)
  - Gros, Robert R., 1972 (Folder 12)
  - Gubser, Charles S., 1966-68 (Folder 13)
  - Guiang, Pedro, 1954-1966 (Folder 14)
  - Hamblin, Frank N., 1970 (Folder 15)
  - Hand, Harold, 1954-59 (Folder 16)
  - Hanna, Richard T., 1963-1973 (Folder 17)
  - Hannah, John A., 1955-1970 (Folder 18)
  - Harbison, Frederick, 1962-67 (Folder 19)
  - Hayden, Richard, 1971, 1974 (Folder 20)
  - Herzog, Milan, 1951-1963 (Folder 21)
  - Hess, Robert D., 1972 (Folder 22)
  - High, Sidney, 1973 (Folder 23)
  - Hill, Robert, 1973-75 (Folder 24)
  - Hjelm, Howard F., 1965 (Folder 25)
  - Hodges, Richard, 1967-1976 (Folder 26)
  - Hodgson, John, 1974 (Folder 27)
  - Hoffmann, Glen W., 1975 (Folder 28)
  - Hopcraft, Jack, 1972 (Folder 29)
  - Horowitz, Myer, 1973 (Folder 30)
  - Hoshall, C. Earle, 1963-1968 (Folder 31)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1967-68 (Folder 32)
  - Howard, Bailey K., 1962-68 (Folder 33)
  - Hoyt, Genevieve, 1970-71 (Folder 34)
  - Humphrey, Richard A.
    - 1956-1960 (Folder 35)
    - 1960-62 (Folder 36)
    - 1963-68 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Hunt, John, 1975 (Folder 2)
  - Huntley, Milburn J., 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Ike, Vincent Chukwuemeka, 1969-1971 (Folder 4)
  - Inkeles, Alex, 1970 (Folder 5)
  - The Instructor, 1960 (Folder 6)
  - International Institute of Arts and Letters, 1961-63 (Folder 7)
  - International Institute for Education Planning, 1966 (Folder 8)
  - Isidro, Antonio, 1973 (Folder 9)
  - Jacobs, Ethel and Harold, 1951-1962 (Folder 10)
  - Jacobson, David S., 1954-58 (Folder 11)
  - James, H. Thomas, 1967 (Folder 12)
  - Jenkins, Robert, 1975-76 (Folder 13)
  - Johnson, Marcella, 1972-75 (Folder 14)
  - Johnson Foundation, 1966 (Folder 15)
  - Jones, Howard P.
    - 1965-68 (Folder 16)
    - 1969-1974 (Folder 17)
  - Kaigo, Tokiomi, 1969-1975 (Folder 18)
  - Kappa Delta Pi (Laureate Chapter), 1963-65 (Folder 19)
  - Kennedy, Sister, 1978 (Folder 20)
  - Kepple, Francis, 1962-64 (Folder 21)
  - King, Richard, 1969-1971 (Folder 22)
  - Kinney, Lucien B., 1955-1961 (Folder 23)
  - Kohn, Clyde, 1970-72 (Folder 24)
  - Kuchel, Thomas H., 1963-67 (Folder 25)
  - Lacey, Albert, 1971-73 (Folder 26)
  - Lamson, Robert, 1973 (Folder 27)
  - Land, Edwin, 1970 (Folder 28)
  - Lawson, Bernice, 1970-71 (Folder 29)
  - Layne, Pat, 1972 (Folder 30)
  - Lee, Hahn-Been, 1972-73 (Folder 31)
  - Lee, John, 1970-74 (Folder 32)
  - Lee, Russel, 1976 (Folder 33)
  - Lindeman, John, 1968 (Folder 34)
  - Lyons, Raymond, 1971 (Folder 35)
  - McCoy, Peter, 1972 (Folder 36)
  - McCusker, H.F., 1971 (Folder 37)
  - McFadden, James, 1972 (Folder 38)
  - McIntyre, Peter, 1973 (Folder 39)
  - McNally, Harold J., 1974 (Folder 40)
  - Manley, Frank J., 1957-1960 (Folder 41)
  - Manning, Bayless, 1972 (Folder 42)
  - Maples, Mrs. Roscoe, 1969 (Folder 43)
  - Mawby, Russell G., 1972 (Folder 44)
  - Mitchell, Larry E., 1970 (Folder 45)
  - Mizota, George, 1975 (Folder 46)
  - Moffat, Samuel, 1975 (Folder 47)
  - Moore, F.J., 1974 (Folder 48)
  - Moore, Frank, 1973 (Folder 49)
  - Morris, Mrs. Emory W., 1974 (Folder 50)
  - Mosher, A.T., 1971 (Folder 51)
  - Mun, Hui Sok, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Murray, Douglas P., 1971 (Folder 2)
  - My Weekly Reader (Advisor Editor), 1965-1970 (Folder 3)
  - Mylecraine, Rosemary, 1973-74 (Folder 4)
  - Nagel, Gunthe, 1975 (Folder 5)
  - Nault, William H., 1975 (Folder 6)
  - Negewo, Beyene, 1980 (Folder 7)
  - Nelson, Murry, 1976 (Folder 8)
  - Newman, Robert E., 1969 (Folder 9)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1961, 1970 (Folder 10)
  - Nystrom & Co., A.J., 1965 (Folder 11)
  - O'Brien, Richard F., 1967 (Folder 12)
  - Odell, William R., 1963-64 (Folder 13)
  - Oswald, James M., 1976 (Folder 14)
  - Pace, Frank, 1965-67 (Folder 15)
  - Page, Raymond, 1974 (Folder 16)
  - Palmer, Ray, 1975 (Folder 17)
  - Palmer, William A., 1971-72 (Folder 18)
  - Parkyn, George, 1972 (Folder 19)
  - People to People, 1966 (Folder 20)
  - Peralta, Cresencio, 1970-71 (Folder 21)
  - Peterson, David, 1974 (Folder 22)
  - Peterson, George L., 1972 (Folder 23)
  - Phi Delta Kappa, 1963-64 (Folder 24)
  - Phi Delta Kappan, 1962-68 (Folder 25)
  - Phillips, Lynn, 1975 (Folder 26)
  - Pierce, Diane B., 1973 (Folder 27)
  - Pike, Tomas, 1969 (Folder 28)
  - Pinar, William, 1973 (Folder 29)
  - Platt, William, 1969-1972 (Folder 30)
  - Poe, Dison, 1973 (Folder 31)
  - Poniatoff, Alexander M., 1974 (Folder 32)
  - Potter, Gladys, 1969-1972 (Folder 33)
  - Pribram, Karl, 1967-68 (Folder 34)
  - Risteen, Landon, 1967 (Folder 35)
  - Rossini, Frederick D., 1970-71 (Folder 36)
  - Rudorf, Hugh, 1968 (Folder 37)
  - Rugg, Harold, 1955-59 (Folder 38)
  - Ryan, John, 1973-76 (Folder 39)
  - Scates, Alice Y., 1973 (Folder 40)
  - Scoles, Edward A., 1957-1961 (Folder 41)
  - Seay, Maurice, 1972 (Folder 42)
  - Seller, Tom, 1969-1972 (Folder 43)
  - Shanahan, John, 1972-73 (Folder 44)
  - Shipp, Frederic T., 1956-1962 (Folder 45)
  - Slipher, Dave, 1968 (Folder 46)
  - Smelt, Mrs. E.D., 1970-72 (Folder 47)
  - Softky, Marion H., 1973 (Folder 48)
  - Sowards, Wesley G., 1969-1975 (Folder 49)
  - Spaeth, Carl, 1963-1964 (Folder 50)
  - Spaulding, Seth J., 1973 (Folder 51)
  - Spaulding, William, 1969-1975 (Folder 52)
  - Staley, Eugene A., 1969-1975 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Standard Oil Company, 1948-49 (Folder 2)
  - Starr, Wilmarth H., 1958-1960 (Folder 3)
  - Sterling, J.E. Wallace, 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Stiles, Lindley, J., 1973 (Folder 5)
  - Stone, Norman and Karen, 1970-71 (Folder 6)
  - Stone, W. Clement, 1973 (Folder 7)
  - Striplin, Harvey, 1972 (Folder 8)
  - Sullivan, Graham, 1967-1968 (Folder 9)
  - Sunset Magazine Publishing Company, 1958 (Folder 10)
  - Tamano, Mauyag, 1969-1976 (Folder 11)
  - Tan, Vidal, 1953-1966 (Folder 12-13)
  - Taylor, Roger, 1974 (Folder 14)
  - Tengelsen, Walter, 1967-68 (Folder 15)
  - Todd, Oliver, 1973 (Folder 16)
  - Tonnar, Wiley B., 1954-58 (Folder 17)
  - Trans World Airlines, Inc., 1966-67 (Folder 18)
  - Tresidder, Donald B., 1943-46 (Folder 18A)
  - Trethaway, Edwin H., 1963-68 (Folder 19)
  - Tunney, John, 1976 (Folder 20)
  - Tyler, Ralph, 1958-1968 (Folder 21)
  - UNESCO, 1954-1965 (Folder 22)
  - University of California Extension, 1968 (Folder 23)
  - Usprech, Celia, 1972 (Folder 24)
  - Van Der Oord, W.J., 1973 (Folder 25)
  - Van Duyn, Robert, 1963-68 (Folder 26)
  - Van Vorst, William, 1969-1973 (Folder 27)
  - Ver Steeg, Clarence, 1970 (Folder 28)
  - Vickers, Daisy U., 1956-1961 (Folder 29)
  - Waller, Theodore, 1970-71 (Folder 30)
  - Warner, Leslie, 1973 (Folder 31)
  - Weiler, Hans N., 1969-1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Weller, Thomas, 1973-74 (Folder 2)
  - Whitaker, Douglas, 1955-1961 (Folder 3)
  - White House, 1970 (Folder 4)
  - Wilde, Wilf, 1970-73 (Folder 5)
  - Willis, Benjamin C., 1959-1966 (Folder 6)
  - Wilsey, H. Lawrence
    - 1955-1964 (Folder 7)
    - 1969-1976 (Folder 8)
  - Wong, Ruth, 1969-1971 (Folder 9)
  - World Affairs Council, 1956-1964 (Folder 10)
  - Young, Robert, 1976 (Folder 11)
- PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, 1900-1983 (Boxes 18-34)
  Minutes of meetings, clippings, reports, lists, graphs, pamphlets, charts, studies, and other materials pertaining to Paul Hanna's professional activites as educator filed chronologically and by subject.
  - General (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Chronological file
    - 1900-1933 (Folder 13)
    - 1939 (Folder 14)
    - 1940 (Folder 15)
    - 1942 (Folder 16)
    - 1943 (Folder 17)
    - 1945 (Folder 18)
    - 1944-47
      - Germany, educational reform (Folder 19)
      - Panama Canal Zone assignment (Folder 20)
    - 1947-1948, air affairs (Folder 21)
    - 1948 (Folder 22)
    - 1948-1949, offer, Deputy Director of Army Operations Research, the Johns Hopkins University (Folder 23)
    - 1949 (Folder 24)
    - 1950-1951, air affairs (Folder 25)
    - 1952, U.S. aid to the Philippines (Folder 26)
    - 1953, U.S. aid to the Philippines (Folder 27)
    - 1954 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1955
      - General (Folder 2)
      - February 28-March 5, conference, Southeast Asian Conference on Education, Manila, Philippines (Folder 3)
      - March 24-26, conference, Elementary Education, Texas Elementary Principals and Supervisors Association and the University of Texas, Austin, Texas (Folder 4)
      - April 3-6, conference, Elementary School Administrators, California Department of Education, Santa Rosa, California (Folder 5)
    - 1956
      - General (Folder 6)
      - February 4, conference, Audio-Visual Association of California, Sacramento, California (Folder 7)
      - February 9, Stanford University press release, P. Hanna named to Committee on Institutional Projects Abroad (Folder 7A)
      - March 8, speaking engagement, Rotary Club of Manila, Philippines (Folder 8)
      - July 2, speaking engagement, Department of Elementary School Principals, National Education Association, Portland, Oregon (Folder 9)
    - 1957
      - General (Folder 10)
      - January 7, conference, Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands Department of Education, Truk, East Caroline Islands (Folder 11)
      - May, conference, School Superintendents, Baguio City, Philippines (Folder 12)
      - September 19, speaking engagement, "The Community School, Mackinac (Folder 13)
      - October 31, speaking engagement, meeting of the administrative and supervisory staff, Board of Education, Chicago, Illinois (Folder 14)
      - November 22, conference, Educational Aspects of a Research Project on Overseas Programs of American Universities, Institute of Research on Overseas Programs, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan (Folder 15)
      - November 30, conference, National Council for the Social Studies, Pittsburg, Pennsylvania (cancelled) (Folder 16)
    - 1958
      - General (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - January 6, Stanford University press release, P. Hanna's travels in the Far East (Folder 1A)
      - March 11, convention, American Assocation of School Administrators, San Francisco Regional, San Francisco, California (Folder 2)
      - March 24-25, conference, Planning a Program for a Teachers' College, Board of Education, Chicago, Illinois (Folder 3)
      - April 8, Stanford University press release, P. Hanna receives Philippine Public School Teachers Association award (Folder 3A)
      - June, Eldorado County seminars (Folder 4)
      - June 30-August 13, faculty, Harvard Summer School (Folder 5)